<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
    <channel>
		<title>News - Austin American-Statesman</title>
		<atom:link href="https://www.statesman.com/news?template=rss&amp;mime=xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news</link>
		<description>statesman.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 01:24:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<item>
		<title>Hospice patients&amp;rsquo; families struggle with Austin coronavirus isolation orders</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/hospice-patientsrsquo-families-struggle-with-austin-coronavirus-isolation-orders?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 19:00:29 CST</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Heather OsbourneBronte Wittpenn</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/hospice-patientsrsquo-families-struggle-with-austin-coronavirus-isolation-orders</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ynthia Merka&rsquo;s eyes opened for a few brief moments soon after her husband&rsquo;s hand slid into hers at a hospice center in East Austin late Tuesday.The 43-year-old&rsquo;s husband, Eric Merka, and her mother and father, Truman and Jane Miller, sat in near silence as they absorbed the last few moments together before the city&rsquo;s mandatory stay-at-home order sparked by the coronavirus pandemic went into effect at midnight.The new orders meant only two family [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Coronavirus in Sun City: Seniors use golf carts to visit neighbors</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/coronavirus-in-sun-city-seniors-use-golf-carts-to-visit-neighbors?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 19:00:28 CST</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Claire Osborn</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/coronavirus-in-sun-city-seniors-use-golf-carts-to-visit-neighbors</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[GEORGETOWN &mdash; Missing their usual get-togethers, a small group of Sun City residents took to their golf carts Wednesday evening, driving separately around the neighborhood to chat with neighbors &mdash; from an appropriate social distance.Sun City, a retirement community in Georgetown, has closed its golf course and sports courts, along with its amenity centers, and has prohibited fishing in its ponds to help prevent the spread of the coronavirus."A lot of people [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Medics revive second drowning victim Thursday after 55 minutes of CPR, EMS says</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/medics-revive-second-drowning-victim-thursday-after-55-minutes-of-cpr-ems-says?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 18:43:28 CST</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Heather Osbourne</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/medics-revive-second-drowning-victim-thursday-after-55-minutes-of-cpr-ems-says</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Medics have revived a person who was reportedly drowning in Waller Creek, Austin-Travis County EMS said Thursday evening.Medics responded around 7 p.m. to reports of a drowning at East Sixth Street and Sabine Street in Waller Creek, EMS said. They were able to regain a pulse after 55 minutes of CPR, medics said.The victim was taken to Dell Seton Medical Center in critical condition, EMS said.It was the second drowning reported Thursday evening. Medics said [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>3 severely burned after possible explosion in Manor, officials say</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/3-severely-burned-after-possible-explosion-in-manor-officials-say?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 18:33:28 CST</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Heather Osbourne</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/3-severely-burned-after-possible-explosion-in-manor-officials-say</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Austin-Travis County EMS medics are on the scene of a possible explosion in Manor, officials said Thursday evening.Medics, firefighters and police officers are responding to the 11400 block of Austex Acres Lane in Manor, EMS said in a tweet.Two medical helicopters have responded and are transporting two of the victims. All three victims are being taken to Dell Seton Medical Center with critical life-threatening injuries, EMS said.Travis County firefighters [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Alex Jones must pay legal fees for `frivolous' Sandy Hook appeal</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/alex-jones-must-pay-legal-fees-for-frivolous-sandy-hook-appeal?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 18:10:28 CST
</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jonathan Tilove</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/alex-jones-must-pay-legal-fees-for-frivolous-sandy-hook-appeal</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The 3rd Court of Appeals Wednesday denied Alex Jones&#8217; motion to dismiss a defamation lawsuit brought by a Sandy Hook parent and ordered Jones to pay $22,500 in attorney fees for what they found to be a frivolous appeal.That means that Jones has now been assessed nearly $150,000 in legal fees in two cases - one for defamation and another for intentional infliction of emotional distress - brought by Neil Heslin, whose 6-year-old son, Jesse Lewis, was one of the 20 first- [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Coronavirus in Austin: Council approves eviction moratorium in slate of relief measures</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/coronavirus-in-austin-council-approves-eviction-moratorium-in-slate-of-relief-measures?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 17:55:28 CST</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Philip Jankowski</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/coronavirus-in-austin-council-approves-eviction-moratorium-in-slate-of-relief-measures</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Austin City Council passed a slate of items Thursday designed to tamp down the negative economic impact of the coronavirus pandemic.The action comes as recent stay-at-home restrictions have shuttered most businesses in the city in an effort to contain the spread of the outbreak. An untold amount of Austinites have lost their jobs or been furloughed as a result.The council passed the following measures:&bull; A resolution to give City Hall staff more [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>BREAKING: All Bastrop County school districts extend closures to April 19 amid coronavirus</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/breaking-all-bastrop-county-school-districts-extend-closures-to-april-19-amid-coronavirus?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 17:02:28 CST
</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andy Sevilla</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/breaking-all-bastrop-county-school-districts-extend-closures-to-april-19-amid-coronavirus</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Bastrop County&rsquo;s four school districts are extending their closures through April 19 to help protect the health and safety of students, staff and the community amid the coronavirus pandemic, the districts announced Thursday evening.The districts said the extended closure decision was made jointly by the districts&rsquo; superintendents and in consultation with Bastrop County Judge Paul Pape, who is the county&rsquo;s emergency management director.The Bastrop and [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>New Braunfels man with coronavirus dies, Comal County official say </title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/new-braunfels-man-with-coronavirus-dies-comal-county-official-say?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 16:32:28 CST</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kelsey Bradshaw</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/new-braunfels-man-with-coronavirus-dies-comal-county-official-say</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[5:30 p.m. update: Comal County officials Thursday said a New Braunfels man diagnosed with COVID-19, the illness linked to the new coronavirus, has died.The man, who was in his 40s, died Thursday afternoon at Ascension Seton Medical Center in Austin, where he had been treated, county officials said in a statement."Our hearts, as well as our thoughts and our prayers, go out to this man&rsquo;s family and friends," County Judge Sherman Krause said in the [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Paxton sues over price gouging amid coronavirus threat</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/paxton-sues-over-price-gouging-amid-coronavirus-threat?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 16:16:28 CST
</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nicole Cobler</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/paxton-sues-over-price-gouging-amid-coronavirus-threat</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton filed a lawsuit Thursday against Houston-based Auctions Unlimited LLC, which made headlines for auctioning breathing masks and other protective gear as hospitals around the country run low on supplies during the coronavirus  [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Latest: US leads world in confirmed coronavirus cases</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/nationworld/20200326/latest-us-leads-world-in-confirmed-coronavirus-cases?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 16:11:29 CST
</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Associated Press, </dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/nationworld/20200326/latest-us-leads-world-in-confirmed-coronavirus-cases</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Latest on the coronavirus pandemic. The new coronavirus causes mild or moderate symptoms for most people, but for some, especially older adults and people with existing health problems, it can cause more severe illness or death.]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Hays County confirms 13 coronavirus cases </title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/hays-county-confirms-13-coronavirus-cases?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 15:57:27 CST
</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alejandro Martinez-Cabrera</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/hays-county-confirms-13-coronavirus-cases</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hays County on Thursday reported two new confirmed cases of people who have the coronavirus, bringing the county&rsquo;s total of positive tests to 13.All 13 people are adults. One of the original positive cases &mdash; a Kyle resident &mdash; has recovered and is out of quarantine, Hays County officials said.The Hays County Local Health Department has so far received 131 negative test results, and 21 test results are pending, county officials said.The [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Coronavirus fallout: Austin restaurant owners face rent due on April 1 </title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/business/20200326/coronavirus-fallout-austin-restaurant-owners-face-rent-due-on-april-1?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 15:37:28 CST
</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lori HawkinsShonda Novak</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/business/20200326/coronavirus-fallout-austin-restaurant-owners-face-rent-due-on-april-1</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For Austin restaurants struggling to survive through take-out orders, there is another looming threat: Rent is due on April 1.Many are telling landlords, property owners and property management firms that due to financial fallout from the coronavirus, they can&rsquo;t pay their rent.Restaurant owners say some landlords are being flexible -- but some others want full rent paid on Wednesday.Operators with multiple locations are finding themselves negotiating [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Killeen police arrest man in February hit and run </title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/killeen-police-arrest-man-in-february-hit-and-run?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 15:21:28 CST</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Heather Osbourne</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/killeen-police-arrest-man-in-february-hit-and-run</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Killeen police arrested a man whom they accuse of hitting a pedestrian with his pickup truck and left him injured in the street.Officers were sent to the 1100 block of FM 440 at around 11 p.m. on Feb. 26 after reports of a hit and run, police said in a statement Thursday.Police found a man lying in the road in critical condition, according to officers. The man was immediately taken to Baylor Scott & White Health, police said.Investigators said a driver of a [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>UPDATE: 17-year-old killed in North Austin stabbing, roommate arrested, police say</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/update-17-year-old-killed-in-north-austin-stabbing-roommate-arrested-police-say?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 15:19:28 CST</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kelsey Bradshaw</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/update-17-year-old-killed-in-north-austin-stabbing-roommate-arrested-police-say</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A 17-year-old was killed in a stabbing at a North Austin apartment complex Thursday morning, Austin police said.At around 2:25 a.m., police received a 911 call from a person saying they found Julio Enrique Saqui Tzalam stabbed inside an apartment complex in the 7200 block of Duval Street, Austin police Lt. Matthew Wright said.The apartments are in an area just west of Interstate 35 near St. Johns Avenue.Medics gave the 911 caller CPR instructions over the [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>In face of the coronavirus, Texas Democrats will hold virtual convention</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/in-face-of-coronavirus-texas-democrats-will-hold-virtual-convention?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 14:52:28 CST
</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jonathan Tilove</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/in-face-of-coronavirus-texas-democrats-will-hold-virtual-convention</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Bowing to the new reality, the Texas Democratic Party announced Thursday that its state convention, scheduled for June 4-6 at the Henry B. Gonz&aacute;lez Convention Center in San Antonio, will now be an online event."Our virtual experience will be fun, exciting and keep everybody safe during this difficult time," said Texas Democratic Party Chairman Gilberto Hinojosa, who said the spread of COVID-19 required a move that he said will be matched by innovation.The party [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Coronavirus live updates: With $2 trillion stimulus near, stocks rally despite record unemployment claims; death toll rises in NY</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/zz/news/20200326/coronavirus-live-updates-with-2-trillion-stimulus-near-stocks-rally-despite-record-unemployment-claims-death-toll-rises-in-ny?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 14:50:31 CST</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>John Bacon and Lindsay Schnell, USA TODAY</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/zz/news/20200326/coronavirus-live-updates-with-2-trillion-stimulus-near-stocks-rally-despite-record-unemployment-claims-death-toll-rises-in-ny</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On a day when jobless claims smashed a record and U.S. deaths surged past 1,100&nbsp;as the coronavirus tightened its grip on America, the prospect of a&nbsp;stimulus package soon becoming reality helped propel a third&nbsp;consecutive stock market rally Thursday.The Labor Department, in announcing the unemployment claims numbers for last week, said what Americans already knew &ndash;&nbsp;that layoffs hit the&nbsp;hospitality and food service industries particularly hard. Other [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>COVID-19 will overwhelm Austin-area hospitals unless social contact is drastically cut, UT researchers say </title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/covid-19-will-overwhelm-austin-area-hospitals-unless-social-contact-is-drastically-cut-ut-researchers-say?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 14:37:27 CST
</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lara Korte</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/covid-19-will-overwhelm-austin-area-hospitals-unless-social-contact-is-drastically-cut-ut-researchers-say</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Researchers at the University of Texas say hospitals in the Austin-Round Rock area will be overwhelmed by coronavirus cases unless the community takes action to drastically reduce person-to-person contact.In the report released Thursday, lead author and UT professor Lauren Ancel Meyers presented a number of scenarios based on the assumed rate of transmission and the severity of the coronavirus for [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Williamson County coronavirus cases increase to 27</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/williamson-county-coronavirus-cases-increase-to-27?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 14:32:28 CST</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Claire Osborn</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/williamson-county-coronavirus-cases-increase-to-27</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Williamson County Cities and Health District has announced that the number of coronavirus cases in the county has increased to a total of 27. There have been no deaths, officials said.Five new cases were announced Thursday. The 27 confirmed cases include six in Cedar Park, six in Georgetown and four in Leander. They also include seven in Round Rock and four in the part of Austin that is in Williamson County.Ten of the people with coronavirus are male and 17 are [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Herman: Coronavirus pandemic, pizza, chips and love</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/herman-coronavirus-pandemic-pizza-chips-and-love?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 14:31:29 CST</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ken Herman</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/herman-coronavirus-pandemic-pizza-chips-and-love</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Under the unparalleled pressure of a pandemic, people are being people &mdash; sad and silly, poignant and prayerful, worried while nostalgic for the simple pleasures of a life that, for now, seem to be from a long-ago time gone by."Y&rsquo;all remember how we used to sit down at a Mexican restaurant and they just brought you out free chips and salsa," wrote someone who tweets as Rivey from Dallas.The challenges of our times also have brought valuable reminders that [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Round Rock ISD, other districts donate masks, gloves to fight coronavirus</title>
		<link>https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/round-rock-isd-other-districts-donate-masks-gloves-to-fight-coronavirus?rssfeed=true</link> 
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 14:28:29 CST
</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>By Darcy Sprague, Contributing writer</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.statesman.com/news/20200326/round-rock-isd-other-districts-donate-masks-gloves-to-fight-coronavirus</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Round Rock school district on Thursday donated more than 6,500 masks and 6,000 pairs of gloves to Williamson County in an effort to stop the spread of COVID-19.The supplies, along with hundreds more donated by surrounding districts, will be distributed to hospitals and first responders on the front lines of the pandemic.&#8220;It is going to make an immediate impact,&#8221; said Jeffery Yarbrough, district director of safety and security. &#8220;Their response when [...]]]></description>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
